{"Topic": "Railways (2 pages)", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "When was the first train steamed off in India?", "op1": "1848", "op2": "1853", "op3": "1875", "op4": "1880", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the headquarters of the newly established railway zone \u2018East Coast Railways\u2019?", "op1": "Vishakhapattnam", "op2": "Kolkata", "op3": "Hyderabad", "op4": "Bhubaneswar", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which train in India has the longest route length?", "op1": "Howrah - Jammu Tawi Himgiri Express", "op2": "Kanyakumari - Jammu Tawi Himsagar Express", "op3": "Kanyakumari - Dibrugarh Vivek Express", "op4": "Guwahati-Thiruvanthapuram Express", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Where is the Railway Staff College located?", "op1": "Pune", "op2": "Delhi", "op3": "Vadodara", "op4": "Allahabad", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "On which of the following is the longest railway bridge in India located?", "op1": "River Ganges", "op2": "Vembanad Lake", "op3": "River Brahmaputra", "op4": "Chilka Lake", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "In which of the following cities are located 3 zonal headquarters of Indian Railways?", "op1": "Guwahati", "op2": "Mumbai", "op3": "New Delhi", "op4": "Kolkata", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is known for having designed the first railway timetables?", "op1": "George Bradman", "op2": "George Bernard Shaw", "op3": "George Bradshaw", "op4": "George Brummel", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the largest railway junction in India?", "op1": "Delhi", "op2": "Bhatinda", "op3": "Mathura", "op4": "Allahabad", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the eastern-most division of the Indian Railways?", "op1": "Tinsukia", "op2": "Lumding", "op3": "Rangiya", "op4": "Katihar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Over which of the following rivers is the world's highest railway bridge in Kashmir being constructed?", "op1": "Chenab", "op2": "Jhelum", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Indus", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Gorakhpur which has the longest railway platform in the world is located in which of the following states?", "op1": "Odisha", "op2": "West Bengal", "op3": "Uttar Pradesh", "op4": "Chhattisgarh", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following stations has all the three guages viz. broad, metre and narrow?", "op1": "Lucknow", "op2": "Chandigarh", "op3": "Shimla", "op4": "Siliguri", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the width of broad guage railway line in India?", "op1": "5 feet 3 inches", "op2": "5 feet 6 inches", "op3": "4 feet 11 inches", "op4": "5 feet 4 inches", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Match the manufacturing units with their locations", "op1": "A - 3; B - 4; C - 1; D - 2", "op2": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 4; D - 3", "op3": "A - 3; B - 1; C - 4; D - 2", "op4": "A - 3; B - 1; C - 2; D - 4", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following stations was formerly known as Victoria Terminus?", "op1": "Churchgate Railway Station", "op2": "Mumbai Central", "op3": "Lokmanya Tilak Terminus", "op4": "Chhatrapathi Shivaji Terminus", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Fairy Queen, the world's oldest steam locomotive in regular operation, plies between New Delhi and -", "op1": "Shimla", "op2": "Alwar", "op3": "Kalka", "op4": "Gwalior", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first Railway Minister of independent India?", "op1": "John Mathai", "op2": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", "op3": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "op4": "Shanmugham Shetty", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who was the Governor General of India when Railways were first introduced in India?", "op1": "Lord Canning", "op2": "Lord Dalhousie", "op3": "Lord William Bentick", "op4": "Lord Ripon", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which city is the Wheel and Axle Plant of the Indian Railways located?", "op1": "Kapurthala", "op2": "Varanasi", "op3": "Bangalore", "op4": "Rae Barelly", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the rank of India in the world in terms of length of railroad network?", "op1": "First", "op2": "Second", "op3": "Third", "op4": "Fourth", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following ran the first train from Bori Bunder to Thane in 1853?", "op1": "Bombay Baroda Railway", "op2": "The Scindia Railway", "op3": "Central India Railway", "op4": "Great Indian Peninsula Railway", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The Maitree Express connects India with which of the following countries?", "op1": "Myanmar", "op2": "Pakistan", "op3": "Bangladesh", "op4": "Nepal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the largest zone in terms of route kilometers?", "op1": "Western Railways", "op2": "Eastern Railways", "op3": "Northern Railways", "op4": "Southern Railways", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the largest marshalling yard in India (also the longest in Asia)?", "op1": "Mughalsarai", "op2": "Mathura", "op3": "Itarasi", "op4": "Guntakal", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Through which of the following group of states does the Konkan Railways run?", "op1": "Maharashtra - Karnataka - Andhra Pradesh - Kerala", "op2": "Maharashtra - Karnataka - Goa - Kerala", "op3": "Maharashtra - Karnataka - Kerala - Tamil Nadu", "op4": "Karnataka - Goa - Kerala - Tamil Nadu", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following zonal headquarters - city combination is incorrect?", "op1": "South East Central - Bilaspur", "op2": "North Western - Jodhpur", "op3": "East Central - Hajipur", "op4": "West Central - Jabalpur"}, {"Question": "ated pages"}, {"Question": "ts about Indian Railways"}, {"Question": "lway Training & Manufacturing Units"}]}